naturalpartners.com 2016-03-16

# Privacy Policy - Natural Partners

**Effective Date: August 1, 2014**

Natural Partners, Inc. and our affiliates (“Natural Partners”) take seriously the confidentiality of your personal information. The following Privacy Policy sets forth our information gathering and dissemination practices for this website as well as our related sites, application and services (“Natural Partners Sites”). **By accessing or using the Natural Partners Sites, you hereby agree to the terms of this Privacy Policy and consent to the collection and use of information as discussed in this Privacy Policy**. **If you do not agree to the terms of this Privacy Policy, do not access the Natural Partners Sites.**

We respect your privacy. We strive to make your dealings with us as private, easy and secure as possible. We do not sell, rent or loan any of your personally identifiable information to any third party. We may use and share information with those persons and third-party entities specifically involved in the processing of your payment or your application to receive services from Natural Partners; in addition, we may use and share aggregated information that does not uniquely identify you when it enables us to improve and enrich our services and website content. In addition, Natural Partners reserves the right to use and share your information in the event Natural Partners believes doing so is necessary to operate the Natural Partners Sites or where such disclosure may be required by law, or to protect Natural Partner’s right or the rights of others.

Natural Partners reserves the right to modify or amend this Privacy Policy at any time. All changes will be effective immediately upon posting to this website. Material changes will be conspicuously posted on the Natural Partners Sites or otherwise communicated to you. By accessing or using the Natural Partners Sites after such changes are posted you agree and consent to all such changes.

**Non-US Users**

THE NATURAL PARTNERS SITES ARE PROVIDED BY NATURAL PARTNERS, ITS AFFILIATES, AND IT’S VENDORS IN THE UNITED STATES. YOUR PERSONAL INFORMATION WILL BE TRANSFERRED AND MAINTAINED IN NATURAL PARTNERS’ RECORDS IN THE UNITED STATES. IF YOU DO NOT CONSENT TO THIS TRANSFER, DO NOT ACCEPT THIS AGREEMENT OR OTHERWISE USE THE NATURAL PARTNERS SITES.

**Personally Identifiable Account Information**

Natural Partners is meant to be used by health care providers only. Therefore, personally identifiable account information will only be collected from those health care providers who register with our site. Other visitors to this site may still have non-personally identifiable information collected, such as IP Addresses and Cookies (as discussed below).

Natural Partners may collect information you voluntarily share with us in submitting an application for services, as well as other information, for example through Internet Protocol (“IP”) addresses and the use of “cookies,” which may be placed on your computer when you access the website. (See the sections on **IP Addresses** and **Cookies** below.)

Natural Partners may collect any content, record, or electronic communication of any kind, including without limitation your (1) name, (2) specialty, (3) license/certificate number, (4) office contact information, (5) business name and website, (6) address, (7) phone number, (8) email address, (9) financial information, (10) demographic information, and (11) other personal information required to process your application to request services from Natural Partners, so that we may provide you with the information or services that you request, and so that we may communicate with you and send you information and materials for marketing and other purposes, subject to applicable laws and the terms of the Privacy Policy.

Natural Partners maintains full rights to any information collected on the Natural Partners Sites, and may freely collect, use and disclose such information unless prohibited by this Privacy Policy or applicable law. In the event of a change in control of Natural Partners or sale by Natural Partners of substantially all of its assets, any information owned by or in the control of Natural Partners may be transferred to such Natural Partners successor, who will comply with the terms of this Privacy Policy.

**Social Media Content**

Natural Partners is active on social media, including Facebook, Twitter, YouTube, Pinterest, and LinkedIn. You have the opportunity to comment on these websites regarding Natural Partners and the products and services we offer. Natural Partners reserves the rights to post on its websites any comments or content you post on our social media pages. Natural Partners will be held harmless and without liability for the results of any and all third party reposts to any and all other locations, including the direct or assumed meaning regarding content from all company social media websites.

**IP Addresses**

Natural Partners logs IP addresses for systems administration purposes. This information only helps us determine how often different areas of our site are visited. We do not link IP address to any information that is personally identifiable.

**Cookies**

Natural Partners may use cookies to track the use of our websites and to facilitate and enhance your experience on the Natural Partners Sites. “Cookies” are small pieces of information that are stored by your browser on your computer’s hard drive. Our cookies enable us to facilitate access to different aspects of our website. For example, by showing when and how you and others visit the Natural Partners Sites, cookies help us to see which pages of the website are popular and which are not. Cookies can also help us to improve your enjoyment of the Natural Partners Sites, for example, by remembering your address or other personal information when you request information or services on the websites.

Most web browsers automatically accept cookies, but you can disable this function so that your browser will not accept cookies. Please be aware that disabling this function may impact your use and enjoyment of the Natural Partners Sites.

**De-Identified Aggregate Information**

Natural Partners may also aggregate information we collect by de-identifying identifiable information and combining it with other non-identifiable information to calculate and monitor the number and demographics of users of the Natural Partners Sites.

**Credit Card Information**

We do not collect credit card information for payment for any products or services you may order from the Natural Partners Sites. Natural Partners contracts with a third party service provider that complies with the payment card industry standards (PCI) to collect and process your credit card information. We do not store or maintain any credit card information.

**Access by Children:**

The Natural Partners Sites are not directed toward children under 13 years of age and Natural Partners does not knowingly collect or use information from children under 13 through the Natural Partners Sites.

**E-mail Communication**

Natural Partners may use your personal information to send you promotional communications. You have the opportunity to opt-out of receiving such promotional communications from us at any time. To discontinue your receipt of such promotional communications, simply opt out using the link on company webpage.

**Security**

We limit access to personally identifiable information about you to our employees and third-party agents who we reasonably believe need to have access to your information to provide you with the information or services you request from Natural Partners.

The Natural Partners Sites have security measures in place to help protect against the loss, misuse and alteration of the information under our control. While we cannot guarantee that loss, misuse or alteration to data will not occur, Natural Partners uses industry standards, such as Secure Socket Layers (“SSL”) technology, to help safeguard against such occurrences. In certain areas, the information passed between your browser and our system is encrypted with SSL technology to create a protected connection between you and our websites to ensure confidentiality. In the event that a breach into our security systems occurs and there is a possibility that an unauthorized person acquires your personal information, Natural Partners will notify you of such a breach under applicable law

**Access to Your Personal Information**

If you wish to have access to your personal information in our records, please contact us with your request at [info@naturalpartners.com](mailto:info@naturalpartners.com) You may also request that we update your personal information or correct any factual errors that you believe may exist regarding this information.

**Opt-Out Policy**

You may opt-out of receiving our electronic communications at any time by following the in-message instructions to be removed from our mailing list. Please note that removing yourself from our mailing list does not terminate your registration to use the Site. Even if you remove yourself from our email list, we will still retain your personal information in connection with your registration to use the Natural Partners Sites and you may still receive communications with respect to such usage.

**Third-Party Websites**

The Natural Partners Sites may link to, or be linked to, other websites not maintained by or related to Natural Partners. Natural Partners is not responsible for the privacy policies or practices of any third parties or third-party websites, including any linked or linking websites. To the extent that you disclose personally identifiable information to any such third parties, different rules may apply to their use and disclosure of personal information that you disclose to them. We encourage you to review the privacy policies of such websites before disclosing your personal information to them. If any term or provision of this Agreement is considered in any way invalid by a court of competent jurisdiction, in all cases the remainder of these terms and conditions will not be affected and will remain valid and enforceable. Clerical errors are subject to correction.

**Contacting Us**

If you have any questions or concerns regarding this Privacy Policy, please contact us at:

Natural Partners, Inc.  
8445 East Hartford Dr.  
Scottsdale, AZ 85255  
888-633-7620  

Natural Partners is proud to be recognized as a Privacy by Design (PbD) Ambassador
